Our next update is the leader of
dedication and great
commission for
[Applause]
I just want to
say
something for your
and you want to create some kind of
mind. I think that these pictures for 15
years in this
room with us right now
you 2013 passed away. We lost daddy and
we lost the Holy Father. But I think
that if there's one thing that's true
and if this room tells that story is
that somewhere in the skies, good people
are together as they
are. The person tonight ironically has a
lot to do with the on the top of these
screens right here. This is Cleveland.
If you've seen these spots, if you
benefited from one of the many, many
wonderful groups he's brought in, then
tonight, the person that you want to
thank is none other than Mr. David
Gilbert. David is born and in this city.
He was Cleveland before Cleveland was
cool. David is someone who grew up in
our community, who knows our community,
and who had a chance. He was offered a
job and said, "No thanks. I'd
ra for those of you who saw just a few
days ago when he began his job, 34% of
our neighbors said I wouldn't recommend
my hometown to anyone." as
always is absolutely gorgeous and
brilliant wife is here. They raised
their kids in their amazing story. But I
want to tell you a personal story. I had
a chance to work with David but he
brought different events to and one of
them was something that nobody thought
we would get and there's something that
needs something tonight and when we were
trying to get the international games
they had a choice between the city of
Boston the city of Washington DC and
little Cleveland and Mayor Frank George
Jackson our 56 mayor said to the
visiting delegates you You can go, you
can go to Washington, but nobody's going
to love you
like as we were walking out, one of the
players said, "Excuse me, excuse me. Do
you work for the city of
Cleveland? I have never been treated by
such respect by police officers as they
are here and she said something when I
tell them you have something to learn
from the city. I remember when the
seniors were here and somebody stopped
me and asked me for directions and I
thought they asked them how they're
doing and they said I want to tell you
something. When I was on the RTA bus
somebody asked me where I was from and
they made me feel home. All of that is
because of the architecture of one day.
He's a lot of things. He's a marathon
runner. He's a humble guy. He's an
award leadership community from the
Jewish American community of which David
is one of our
leaders children's
games senior
games
basketball when he came here to
nationals Anyone in this room, Ukraine,
Russia, Japan, Italy, Slovenia, Croatia,
your
mass and he
says
[Music]
they
for your
for being such a huge honor and
interested in what's
[Music]
happening for relations. I do everything
I can with one senator senator friends
with our
George to do what I can to take the
example of Cleveland around the country
and make sure that we play a rightful
role that we need to play in this world
the way you have
done that doesn't happen by
accident a US senator doesn't come to a
city of a major republican convention
with more ambassadors than ever if there
isn't somebody who's working day and
night to make sure that
happens. We have architects in this
room. One of them is Mr. Richard who's
been so responsible for
internationalizing our city. Another
people with somebody who introduced her
and that was Mr. whose mother used to
say before he went to bed every night.
They drew a line to keep me out. Heretic
rebel won to
f. Oh, but love and David Gilbert had
the wit to win. We drew a circle and
brought them in. Ladies and gentlemen,
David
Heat. Heat.
Uh thank you to my fellow. Thank you
Dan. Uh and to be a memory
blessing
I award very much. Um but this one
called was was uh very personal. Um and
as so much my career trying to bring
people to Cleveland. Thank you so much
to our team that that shares this
passion with me. Um bringing
international groups here. Um it truly
has been a passion. Um and it goes back
starting in 2000 just after the sports
commission started. We've been in
existence for 6 months. Um there were
three of us at the time. organization
read an article about event called the
international children's games and it
happened to be taking place in Hamilton
Ontario. They've been around for about
25 years for the World Team Olympics and
never taking place in North America and
uh we ended up uh putting the team
together to participate in baseball team
and that allowed us to be to try and
bring that to Cleveland. Really didn't
know what it would take. um Mayor Mike
at the time did video for us and we we
put our best foot forward. We met with
the committee and I think thankfully
they really wanted to come to the US and
they said before we left we're coming to
Cleveland 2024 and I remember on the
drive
back two3 of our staff in the car
looking at each other excuse my lang
what the hell did we just get ourselves
and uh um
and not long after
that and um he Let's do this. He got it
immediately and
uh it's because of you successful and so
many people in this room and so being
here just
seeing and generation and um so many
others that are here that help put this
together and learn so much. I have to
say what I learned from Alex a
lot and
We we so many people on this screen, so
many people in this room jumped in,
people I didn't know said, "We're going
to make this great." And because of
those efforts, we have what is still the
largest game in the 50 plus history. We
have 123 cities from 50 plus countries
here. of 3,000 athletes, several
thousand other people from around the
world. It is still as widely considered
probably the best they've ever had and
still talked about as as a moment for
that worldwide event. And it's because
of this community because we embrace
them unlike any other. And I was
fortunate enough for the next almost two
decades to be on that board and
executive committee representing our
great city. We still take teams every
year to participate and uh um and take
take part in that. And I think that
people ask me all these events that have
come to town, what what means the most
cuz that's what taught me that bring
town is not just about the dollars they
spend. It's about a chance for people to
fall in love with our city. And that's
what happens. That's because of the
people in this room here. Every one of
these speakers talk about it. So many
other major international events follow.
Joe mentioned the Gay Games, the Pan
Masters Games just here last summer,
first time ever in the United States.
And and every time every time this is
this no joke, they walk away saying
there's something special about this
city that we don't feel anywhere else.
And every time these meetings,
conventions, major events come to
Cleveland. doesn't happen by accident.
We're we're in competition with cities
from around the country, around the
world, and I think they see our path and
why we want to have them here. But
what's amazing is that that we we chose
to go after them. But almost to to a
person, to an organizing community, to
an event, they walk away feeling
something incredibly incredibly special
about this community. It's just who we
are. Um I I just feel like what what we
have here we embrace, we appreciate, we
celebrate and it's something that makes
this
community very different, very unique
from other places around the world. Um
just I I want to thank all of you um for
making this city so special. Um thank
you to my my beautiful wife as mentioned
for supporting everything I do. I get a
ride home now. Oh yeah, she's my best
[Music]
friend. And thank you for